shldirect.com 2010-05-13

# Privacy

##### Last updated: 17 November 2006

This Privacy Policy describes how SHL Group Limited collects, uses and safeguards personal information that you may provide to us. When we refer to personal information we mean information or an opinion about you, from which your identity is apparent or can be reasonably ascertained.

We are committed to promoting confidence in the manner in which your personal information is handled by us. In this regard, we will act ethically and as evidence of this commitment, we will comply with the privacy and data protection requirements of the countries in which we operate.

##### Contents:

  * \- Collection of personal data 
  * \- Use and disclosure
  * \- Cookies and automatic data collection
  * \- Log files
  * \- Security
  * \- Protection of children's information
  * \- Access to personal information we hold about you
  * \- Your right to challenge
  * \- Privacy compliance
  * \- Complaints Resolution
  * \- Changes to this statement

##### Collection of personal data

In general, you can visit SHL web sites without telling us who you are and without revealing any information about yourself. However there may be occasions when you choose to give us personal information.  Generally this will be for the purposes of:

  * \- receiving further information from us or; 
  * \- for recruitment, selection and development purposes by potential employers, managing recruitment and human resource processes and any related purpose where you have consented to the collection.

We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations. We do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than those indicated above and will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you.

If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, we offer you the means to consent to this new purpose by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected.

##### Use and disclosure

If we require you to provide certain personal information about yourself for the purposes described above, we will not rent, sell or exchange information about you to third parties except to your employers or potential employers, where you consent, where you would reasonably expect the information to be disclosed or where we are legally required to disclose such information.

##### Cookies and automatic data collection

We may automatically log personal data or link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals. However, we will only use this information to help us respond to queries you may have about our products or services or to tell you about other SHL products and services which we think may be of interest to you. We will not pass this information on to any third parties. The Internet browser that you use may make use of a feature called a "cookie" to assign identification to your computer. We do not use cookies to store personal data or to link personal data to non-personal data, unless you have first agreed to this by selecting the "Remember Me" option. If you select this option a cookie will be placed on your computer which will allow our website [www.shl.com](http://www.shl.com/) to recognise you when you return to our website. No personal information will be stored in this cookie.

##### Log Files

Like most web site providers, we analyse server log files to collect statistical information about how our web sites are used. This type of information is collected only at an aggregate level and includes browser types, Internet service providers, referring / exit pages, platform types, date/time stamps and other broad demographic data. Such data is not linked to personally identifiable information.

##### Security

We protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information and we have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to do so. SHL operates its own Internet Data Centre that is designed to keep mission critical human resource services and data online and secure at all times.

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:

  * \- Unauthorized access 
  * \- Improper use or disclosure 
  * \- Unauthorised modification 
  * \- Unlawful destruction or accidental loss 

All our employees and data processors, who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data, are required to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data.

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.

##### Protection of children's information

The SHL web sites do not publish content or collect data that is targeted at children.

##### Access to personal information we hold about you

You can ask us whether we are keeping personal data about you. 

Making a request

Requests may be made:

1\. In writing to:

  * \- Ref: PVCSHL  
Data Protection officer  
SHL Group Limited  
The Pavilion  
1 Atwell Place  
Thames Ditton  
Surrey KT7 0NE  
UK
  * \- Requests can be submitted to the above address by printing and completing a Subject Access Request Form (8KB PDF). The purpose of this form is to ensure that you give us all the necessary information to enable us to comply with your request. You do not have to use this form, but if you do not you should ensure that all the required information on this form is provided.

2\. By Email to:

  * \- [privacy@shlgroup.com ](mailto:privacy@shlgroup.com)
  * \- Requests made by email must include all information from the Subject Access Request Form.  The email request must be followed up with written proof of identity (see below). 

Note: The period of 40 days in which the organisation must respond to the request will not commence until we have received written proof of your identity.

**Requests can not be made by telephone or any other means.**

Proof of Identity  
Regardless of the original means of request (letter or email), SHL will require proof of identity before releasing personal data. This may be provided in the following forms:

A paper copy of a bank statement, utility bill or other company letter sent to you, or; 

A paper copy of your driving license, birth certificate, passport or benefits book. 

Proof of identity should be signed and dated by you and sent to the address above with a stamped addressed envelope so that we can send the information that you have requested to you.

What we will send you  
You will be sent a paper notification of:

  * \- Whether SHL is processing personal data about you.
  * \- A description of the data and the purposes of processing the data. (SHL does not disclose personal data to 3rd parties so this information will not be included). 
  * \- An explanation of any codes or abbreviations used so as to make the notification intelligible.
  * \- If we can, information as to the sources of the data.

You may request that the above information is sent to you by email instead.

Fees  
We reserve the right to charge a £10 administration fee for providing this information to you.

Period for Responding  
Your request will be dealt with:

  * \- Within forty days of receipt of the request; or if later 
  * \- Within forty days of receiving the fee and the information needed to verify your identity and locate the information that you seek.

##### Your right to challenge

If at any time you wish to change personal information that is incorrect or wish to have your personal information deleted, please contact us by sending an email to [privacy@shlgroup.com](mailto:privacy@shlgroup.com). Unless personal information is required to be retained by us for administrative or legal reasons, SHL will meet such requests at the earliest possible opportunity by deleting or amending your personal information where appropriate.

##### Privacy compliance

Our privacy policy and compliance with that policy are maintained through a voluntary self-assessment procedure, and compliance with all relevant local laws.  SHL is also certified for US Department of Commerce Safe Harbor.

##### Complaints resolution

We are committed to providing a fair and responsive system for handling and resolving complaints concerning the handling of personal information.  You have a right to complain and to have your complaint handled efficiently if you are concerned about our handling of your personal information.  We believe that any complaint that we may receive is a valuable opportunity to improve the services that we deliver to you and to maintain your confidence in our services.

If at any time you wish to lodge a complaint in respect of the handling, use or disclosure of your personal information by us, you may do so by contacting our Privacy Officer either by sending an email to: [privacy@shlgroup.com](mailto:privacy@shlgroup.com) or at the address below.

We aim to investigate and advise you of the outcome of the complaint promptly.

If you are not satisfied with our handling of your complaint, you may contact your local data protection registrar.

##### Changes to this statement

SHL will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of this privacy statement and post notification of change on web site home pages or other places we deem appropriate.

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [privacy@shlgroup.com](mailto:privacy@shlgroup.com).

Alternatively, you may send questions in writing to:

Ref: PVCSHL  
SHL Group CTO  
SHL Group Limited  
The Pavillion  
1 Atwell Place  
Thames Ditton  
Surrey, KT7 0NE  
UK

Top of page
